<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Answers for Sir John Hall lord provost of Edinburgh, the magistrats, town council, and others. To the complaint exhibited by James McKlurg, George Clerk, Robert Blackwood, VVilliam Paton, and others, against them.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 38 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75451</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3465</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R234722</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45578122</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45578122</idno>
            <idno type="VID">172084</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75451)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 172084)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2613:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Answers for Sir John Hall lord provost of Edinburgh, the magistrats, town council, and others. To the complaint exhibited by James McKlurg, George Clerk, Robert Blackwood, VVilliam Paton, and others, against them.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>10 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Sutro Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Hall, John, --  Sir.</term>
               <term>McKlurg, James.</term>
               <term>Blackwood, Robert.</term>
               <term>Clerk, George.</term>
               <term>Paton, William.</term>
               <term>Edinburgh (Scotland) --  Politics and government.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  Politics and government --  1689-1745.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:172084:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure/>ANSWERS <hi>For Sir</hi> John Hall <hi>Lord Provoſt
of</hi> Edinburgh, <hi>the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrats, Town Council, and others.</hi> To
<hi>The Complaint exhibited by</hi> James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>klurg, George Clerk, Robert
Blackwood, VVilliam Paton, <hi>and others, againſt them.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Sum of the long Libel is this, that the Defenders are factious
perſons, deſigning to perpetuat the Office of Provoſtrie of
<hi>Edinburgh</hi> in the Perſons of Sir <hi>John Hall,</hi> and Sir
<hi>Archibald Muir</hi> by turns, and to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hance and ſquander the
Common-good of the Town, and that the ſaid Sir <hi>John</hi> and <hi>George
Stirling,</hi> by their imprudent Carriage in Parliament, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Royal
Intereſt, occaſioned a great Branch of the Towns Revenue to be cut off by
an Act of Parliament; And that for theſe Deſigns of perpetuating that
Magiſtracy, and inhancing the Common-good to themſelves, they have made
many Invaſions on the Set and Conſtitutions of the Town, by the three
laſt Elections, which the Complainers crave may be reduced, upon ſeveral
pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Violations of the Set; and the Defenders otherways puniſhed
therefore; and in order thereto, the Complainers crave, that the Books and
Regiſters of the Town Council may be produced, and which Libel conſiſting
of two Sheets, back and before, was execute againſt the Defenders upon
<hi>Saturday</hi> in the afternoon, to compear before your Lordſhips this
day.</p>
            <p>For although the Complainers were ſufficiently picqued at the
diſappointment they met with, in not being advanced to places within the Town
according to their expectation, a great while ago, which they themſelves
thought they did de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve (though the plurality of the Town Council was of
another opinion) and conſequently the Complainers have had a conſiderable
time to adviſe and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſult this their long Complaint, yet they never
attempted to raiſe the ſame, till after the death of Sir <hi>James
Rochead,</hi> one of the conjunct Clerks of the Town, that Mr. <hi>David
Dalrymple</hi> his Son in Law, having agreed with <hi>Aeneas Mcleod,</hi> Sir
<hi>James</hi> his Conjunct, to get his Good-will of the half of that Office,
the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainers knew, that the receiving or not receiving of a Clerk, was in
the power of the Defenders, and that they had grounds to believe that the
Defenders would not receive Mr. <hi>David</hi> in that Office; ſo they would
have the ſettled Magiſtracy of the Metrapolitan overturned, to make way for
their own Advancement, and the Inſtalment of Mr. <hi>David</hi> in the
foreſaid Office: For within an hour after the Execution of the Libel
againſt the Provoſt, Mr. <hi>David</hi> propoſed to him, and 
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:172084:2"/>thereafter to Baillie <hi>Chieſly,</hi> that the Town
Council would enter him to his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in Law's place, which Favour Mr.
<hi>David</hi> would not have demanded from a Magiſtrate, which he thought
was preſently to fall, even though they had grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed his deſire, but would
rather have been obliged for that Complement to <hi>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>lurg</hi> his
Couſin, who (as the Complainers give out) is to ſuceed the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voſt if
they prevail.</p>
            <p>As the Factiouſneſs of the Defenders, they humbly repreſent
to your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips, in all ſincerity, that they are of no Faction, neither
<hi>Jacobite</hi> nor <hi>Epiſcopal,</hi> but are perſons well affected to
the preſent Government, both of Church and State, and that they have no
intriguing with ſuch diſaffected perſons, whatever Friendſhip the
Complainers may have from ſuch, and whatever Inclinations the Diſaffected
within this Town may have ſhown, to have the Complainers brought into the
Magiſtracy; For as Sir <hi>John Hall</hi> and <hi>George Stirling,</hi> their
Zeal and Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection for Their Majeſties Intereſt, did appear in their
hearty and chearfull Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>currance in the late happy Revolution, as Members of
the Convention of Eſtates, repreſenting this good Town, ſo Sir
<hi>Archibald Muir</hi> made his Loy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and Zeal for this preſent
Government, eminently appear by his inducing of the Neighbours of the Town to
offer to contribute for the Maintainance of a Regiment, for Defence of the
preſent Government, when a dreadful and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Invaſion was threatned
from <hi>France,</hi> and of which Offer your Lordſhips need not to be
remembred.</p>
            <p>As to Sir <hi>John Hall</hi> and <hi>Sir Archibald Muir</hi>'s
deſign, to perpetuat themſelves Provoſts of <hi>Edinburgh</hi> by turns,
though it be the great Drift and Scope of the long Libel, and many far fetched
Conſequences, and Repetitions uſed to evince and make out that Deſign
againſt the Defenders; yet the Sum of all is, that Sir <hi>John</hi> was
firſt Provoſt, and that Sir <hi>Archibald</hi> ſucceeded upon his
Dimiſſion, and that Sir <hi>John</hi> was elected at <hi>Michaelmaſs</hi>
laſt, when Sir <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chibald</hi> went off; Yet that Sir <hi>John</hi> was
firſt legally Elected, the Complainers cannot contravert, and that Sir
<hi>Archibald</hi> ſucceeded him, cannot infer the Deſign of perpetuating
the Office betwixt them, ſince it is imppoſſible, but that one Man muſt
ſucceed another; beſide, Sir <hi>John</hi> had no hand in the Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of
Sir <hi>Archibald,</hi> having voted both for Leeting and Electing
<hi>Archibald Hamilton:</hi> So that the Deſign is only inferred from this
ſingle Act, that Sir <hi>John</hi> is now Elected after Sir
<hi>Archibald;</hi> when <hi>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>lurg's</hi> Friends offered to lay
Wagers, that he would carry the Vote. But it is a ſtrange Confidence to
in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer from one ſingle Act, a Deſign of perpetuating the Office by turns;
when the Complainers themſelves cannot deny, but that Sir <hi>John</hi> was
abſent all the time that the laſt Election was in Agitation, and that he
was very unwilling to accept of the Office, after he was voted Provoſt, and
which Office he only accepted for the Common good, and not for his private
Intereſt; ſince the Complainers dare not ſay, that he made, or makes any
Advantage by the place; nor could Sir <hi>John</hi> gratifie his Ambition
thereby, having had the Honour before, of being choſen Provoſt by the
popular Election in a critical time: and continued a ſecond year by the
ordinar way of Election.</p>
            <p>As to the Deſign of inhancing, and ſquandering the Towns
Money, it is no ways evinced by any Fact or Deed done by the Defenders, in
inhancing, or ſquandering already any part of the Towns Goods, nor in any
ſuch thing alledged to be done by the Libel, but only the Hundreth Pounds
Sterling given to <hi>William Menzies</hi> (which ſhall get a good Anſwer
in its proper place) And as for the inhancing of the Towns Money, the
Complainers have not the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence <pb n="3" facs="tcp:172084:2"/>to alledge the Defenders
have already done it, or to give any Inſtance thereof, but they would have
them removed, becauſe they may Inhance the ſame hereafter, which if it be a
good Argument, all Magiſtrates may be removed be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe they may Inhance;
But to redargue the Complainers Jealouſies of Inhancing, they know that at
the <hi>Michaelmaſs</hi> 1683. the Town was but in ſix hundreth thouſand
Merks of Debt, which by the Miſmanagment of the Magiſtrates in five or
ſix years extended it to ſeven hundred and ſixty <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap>
thouſand pounds when Sir <hi>John Hall</hi> entered to be Provoſt; for the
former Magiſtrats were in uſe to Borrow Money for payment yearly of their
Annualrents, and expend yearly of incident Charges, <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap>
thouſand pounds or thereby; whereas ſince the Revolution there has no Money
been Borrowed for payment of Annualrents; but on the contrary ſome Principal
Sums have been payed, and the Yearly incident Charges of the Town has not
extended to ſo many hundreds, as it did to thouſands before.</p>
            <p>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to that point of Sir
<hi>John Hall,</hi> and <hi>George Stirling,</hi> their loſing a great Branch
of the Towns Revenves, by their imprudent Carriage in Parliament to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the
Royal Intereſt. It is anſwered, That it is a ſtrange Inſolence in the
Complainers, to quarrel Members of Parliament, for their Carriage in
Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: for which they were not Challenged by the Parliament it ſelf,
ſince it is undeniable, that it is the Freedom of the Members of Parliament
to be Cenſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by none but the Parliament for what they act therein; and the
Parliament did never Cenſure either of them for what they did, as Members
thereof, and the Town was ſo far from being Diſpleaſed with their
Carriage therein, that even af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter that pretended Miſcarriage in Parliament,
they were continued in the Offices of <hi>Provoſt</hi> and
<hi>Deacon-Conveener:</hi> And ſince the Complainers do not condeſcend upon
the Miſcarriage, the Defenders can make no diſtinct Anſwer thereto, but
as they were, and are Members of this current Parliament, ſo they Acted and
Voted in Parliament according to their Oath <hi>de fideli,</hi> and no Man
would offer to Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure and Accuſe Members of Parliament for their Carriage
therein, but theſe that perhaps hereafter may take the liberty to reflect
upon the Acts of Parliament, and the claim of Right, when they touch them, or
their Relations: And as the Complainers cannot condeſcend upon any particular
Miſcarriage of the ſaid Sir <hi>John</hi> and <hi>George</hi> in
Parliament, though the ſame were to be Cognoſced by the Parliament (who are
the only Judge Competent thereto) yet the Complainers miſtake the
conſequence of the pretended Miſcarriage, when they ſay that a Branch of
the Revenue was cut off by an Act of Parliament, for that Branch was the two
pennies on the Pint, whereof the Town had an Arbitrary Grant from the late
<hi>King,</hi> without Conſent of Parliament, which was Condemned as Illegal,
by the Convention of Eſtates, and ſo was not cut off by the Parliament,
whoſe Act did not cut off the ſame, but did Indemnifie the Town for
uplifting Bygones: and granted them a Year thereof in time to come, with a New
Impoſition,<hi>&amp;c.</hi> which was all that the ſaid Sir <hi>John</hi>
and <hi>George</hi> could get done for the Town, notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding that they
us'd their utmoſt Endeavours, to get the two pennies upon the Pint continued
by Act of Parliament for a longer time: So that the ſaids Sir <hi>John</hi>
and <hi>George</hi> their Carriage in Parliament, could not occaſion the
cutting off the two pennies on the Pint by Act of Parliament, which was
contrary to the fundamental Laws of the Kingdom, condemned as Illegal by the
claim of Right, and had been Treaſon in the Town to have Exacted it, without
a New Act of Parliament, unleſs the Complainers be of Opinion, that the Late
<hi>Kings</hi> ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolute diſpenſing power aſſerted by his
Proclamations be yet in Vigour, and that <pb n="4" facs="tcp:172084:3"/>that Branch of the
Revenue would have ſtooden in deſpight of the claim of Right, if the
Parliament had not out of Diſpleaſure at Sir <hi>John Hall</hi> and
<hi>George Stirling,</hi> taken it away. And if the Complainers mean that Sir
<hi>John</hi> and <hi>George</hi> in ſtead of cutting off the Gift, did
hinder the Renewing thereof by the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; It is Anſwered, that they
Voted, according to their Conſciences, and albeit they had had all the
Freedom the Complainers would have adviſed them to, yet as things then
ſtood, the plurality of the Parliament would not have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curred in Renewing
of the Gift.</p>
            <p>The Complaint being a Reduction of three ſucceſſive
Elections. It is alledg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by way of Defence. 1. The Concluſion for Reducing
the two firſt Electi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, cannot be ſuſtained for Annulling the
Elections, or inferring any Cenſure on the Perſons Elected, they having
ſerved out their time, and gone off in courſe before the Elections were
quarrelled: And the Complainers having acquieſced thereto, and concurred with
them in the Council: and Sir <hi>Archibald</hi> having had the Honour to ſit
amongſt Your <hi>Lordſhips,</hi> as <hi>Provoſt</hi> of
<hi>Edinburgh,</hi> while the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vost</hi> was in the Nomination: And Your
<hi>Lordſhips</hi> being Judges to poſſeſſion, when it is unjuſt or
Violent, if the poſſeſſion be ended and paſt, the unjuſt
poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſor, cannot quite the poſſeſſion. And therefore theſe
Magiſtrats not being now in poſſeſſion of the Magiſtracy, cannot be
put out thereof, and although there had been Streaches made at their Election,
and Invaſions upon the Set, yet theſe conſiſting in point of Right,
depending upon the Interpretation of obſcure Clauſes: if the Complainers
Deſign to prevent the like, for the time to come: they ought to inſiſt in
the Declarator, which they raiſed a Year and an half ago, upon the ſame
pretences, which they have Ommitted to do ever ſince that time, being
conſcious of the Weakneſs of their own Cauſe. 2. As to the laſt
Election, the pretended Informalities of the firſt and ſecond Elections,
can be no ground to Annull the ſame: otherways, if ſuch Errors of Election
ſhould influence, and infect ſucceeding Elections, then any Elections of
Magiſtracy might be quarrelled upon Errors done at any time within fourty
years. &amp; all the Deeds done by the ſucceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Magiſtrats, might be
quarrelled upon that Ground. For albeit the Convention of Eſtates by their
Authority, before Their Majeſties acceptation of the Crown, did appoint a
popular Election thorow all the Burghs, becauſe of the manifold Incroachments
had been done by the Government upon their Priviledges, yet it were hard that
Errours and Informalities in Elections occaſioned by the Compe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tition of
Neighbours within Burgh, ſhould ſo far affect ſucceeding Elections, as to
be grounds to annull the ſame when the Election quarrelled it ſelf hath
been moſt regular. And therefore the Election of thir Defenders to the
Magiſtracy, can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be quarrelled upon any Informalities in the two
preceeding Elections. 3, Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hering to the former general defences for taking
off the particular pretended Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>malities of the Elections, it is anſwered
as to the Points quarrelled in Sir <hi>Archi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bald Muir</hi>'s firſt Election.
1. That where the Libellers pretend that after two and twenty of the
Town-Council had Voted to fill up moſt part of the eight Proxies requiſite
to make up the number of thirty, and the Votes ſpliting Eleven to Eleven as
to ſome of theſe Proxies, the Defenders refuſed Baillie <hi>Graham</hi>
the odd Vote which was due to him as firſt Magiſtrat for the time, and
withdrew Tumultuary, though the Complainers Party ſtayed, whereupon the
Libellers made a repreſentation to the Council, and both Parties being heard,
the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders did Boldly and Falſly aſſert that there could be no
Proxies choſen for two old Counſellors who had right to Vote <hi>jure
proprio,</hi> unleſs they had abſented after they were required to come,
whereupon the Council ordained both Parties to begin a new Formal Election, at
which time the Defenders did chuſe eight Proxies <pb n="5" facs="tcp:172084:3"/>over
again, which if it was right, then the firſt Procedure was right, and there
was no place for the new Election of Proxies, and if it was wrong as being
contrary to the Privy Councils Order, then the Election muſt fall.</p>
            <p>To which it is ſhortly Anſwered, That the Procedure of the
Town Council, prior to your Lordſhips Order, was fully debate before your
Lordſhips, where it was evinced, that only the Provoſt had the double Vote
by the Set, and that Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges in Law are <hi>ſtrictiſsimi jur is,</hi>
and that no Baillie did ever claim the ſame, and that there was nothing
diſorderly in the Defenders carriage in withdrawing when the Votes ſplited,
ſince one half of the Council is not ſubject to the other, and the
Libellers party that ſat ſtill being only Eleven (which was not a
<hi>Quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum,</hi> and ſo could not fill up Proxies) that, and not their
Modeſty or Diſcretion was the only ſtop of their Procedure at that time,
and that by the Set <hi>pag.</hi> 15. it is clear that the thirty Leeters are
eighteen of the new Council, and twelve of the old, which twelve are the old
Magiſtrats, three Merchant Counſellors, and two Trades Counſellors, ſo
that <hi>Patrick Johnstoun</hi> and <hi>James Baillie</hi> being old Merchant
Connſellors, had right to Vote <hi>proprio jure,</hi> which the Defenders do
yet aſſert, notwithſtanding of the Libellers calling it a bold and
falſe Aſſertion, which the Complainers may take in better part, ſince
the Libel bears that your Lordſhips took notice thereof, though it was not
thought worthy to be noticed by the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellers in their Debate; and upon which
Debate, your Lordſhips ordained both Parties to proceed to a new formal
Election, and the two old Counſellors to be called to Vote <hi>proprio
jure,</hi> which appointment was obeyed in preciſe terms, and theſe two old
Counſellors called, and ſix other Proxies choſen only to prevent a
Clamour, theſe two Counſellors were not only called <hi>proprio jure</hi>
to Leet, but fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther got a Vote, which was not to make them Proxies, but
approving them to Vote as old Counſellors, which is the Complainers
miſtake, for a voting them Proxies, whereby it is clear, that the firſt
Procedour in voting of eight Proxies was wrong, becauſe the two old
Counſellors had right to vote <hi>proprio jure,</hi> and that the chuſing
of ſix Proxies after your Lordſhips Order, and allowing the two old
Counſellors to vote, was legal and according to your Lordſhips appointment.
And for Baillie <hi>Graham's</hi> pretended odd Vote, it was thought ſuch an
odd Claim by your Lordſhips at that time, that Baillie <hi>Grahame</hi> had
not the confidence to claim it, when your Lordſhips ordered them to proceed
to a new Election. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore to the firſt Nullity, that after your
Lordſhips had ordered a new Election, they chuſed eight Proxies; It is
Anſwered, they chuſed but ſix, and allowed the two old Counſellors to
vote conform to your Lordſhips Interlocutor.</p>
            <p n="2">2. As to that Point, that the Libellers had raiſed a
Declarator before the Lords of Seſſion, and given in a Petition, craving
the ſame might be diſcuſt ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marly, which the Lords appointed to be
ſeen and anſwered, which Deliverance was intimat, notwithſtanding whereof
the Defenders did proceed.</p>
            <p>To this it is anſwered, that the raiſing and executing of a
Declarator, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverances on Bills to ſee and anſwer, does not ſtop
Execution, otherways it were in Parties power to ſtop Execution, by raiſing
Declarators of courſe, and the Lords Ordinance to ſee and anſwer on a
Bill without ſtoping Execution, does not hinder Parties to proceed in the
Execution of their Right, eſpecially when they are warranted thereto by the
Allowance of Their Majeſties Privy Council, ſo that the Defenders having
according to your Lordſhips appointment, prefixt a day for the Election,
before the Intimation of the Lords Deliverance, there was not the leaſt
ground of pretence, for delaying the Election upon that Deliverance.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:172084:4"/>
            <p n="3">3. As to that pretence, that your Lordſhips Ordinance was
upon <hi>Thurſday,</hi> and that upon <hi>Friday</hi> the youngeſt Baillie
called a Council to meet upon <hi>Munday,</hi> upon which day, they both Leeted
and Elected, which was done to prevent the ſitting of the Privy Council and
Seſſion: It is anſwered, that the youngeſt. Baillie may call a Council,
when the elder Baillie will not do it, and that a Council met to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether upon
the Call of any Magiſtrat, is a legal Council, eſpecially when they are
called together by Warrand of the Privy Council, and the youngeſt Baillie his
calling a Council upon the morrow after your Lordſhips Ordinance, cannot be
counted a Fault, being a ready Obedience, and the Council there appointing on
<hi>Fryday, Munday</hi> to be the day for Leeting, is no breach of the Set,
ſince there is no time determined thereby for Intervals betwixt the Leeting
day, and the preceeding Council day: Neither is the Leeting and Electing upon
one day contrair to the Set, unleſs the Dyets were confounded at the ordinary
time of the Election, for when Magiſtrats dimit or die, the method of
Election of their Succeſſors is not determined by the Set, neither is there
the ſame reaſon for the diſtinguiſhing the days of Leeting and Electing
of one Magiſtrat, as when the whole ſeven are to be choſen, and Cuſtom
has cleared the Point, for both Sir <hi>Thomas Kennedy</hi> and Sir <hi>Magnus
Prince</hi> had but one day each of them, both for their being Leeted and
Elected.</p>
            <p n="4">4. As to that Pretence, that Threats and Promiſes were
uſed, to get the thirty perſons Leeters made up to Sir <hi>Archibald
Muir's</hi> Election, and that the Town Penſioners were allowed to Vote
therein, who were excluded to Vote in the popular Election, by the Act of
Convention of Eſtates. It is anſwered, that the Complainers deny the
uſing of Threats or Promiſes upon the Accompt lybelled, albeit the
Lybellers cannot deny, that they and their Accomplices, did actually ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehend
with Caption <hi>George Drummond</hi> late Theaſurer, upon ſuſpition he
would Vote for Sir <hi>Archibald</hi> (and that after they had called him out
of the Council-houſe to the Door) whereby they actually hindred him to Vote
in the Election, neither are Threats and Promiſes for Voting relevant to
annul Elections, unleſs they be made or ordered by the Parties Elected; and
as to the Town Penſioners voting in the Election. It is anſwered, the
Convention of Eſtates debars only Beed-men and Servants to Vote in the
popular Election, but Sir <hi>George Drum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond</hi> and <hi>James Currie,</hi>
who are two of the perſons the Lybellers aim at, are no ſuch perſons, and
were admitted to Vote in the popular Election, and were themſelves Provoſts
of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and may be choſen yet Provoſts of
<hi>Edinburgh,</hi> there being no Limitation in the Set, not to chuſe
Magiſtrats who have Penſions off the Town, and certainly he that may be
choſen Provoſt of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> may Vote in the Election of a
Provoſt of <hi>Edinburgh;</hi> As to <hi>James Baillie</hi> who is the third
perſon, againſt whom the Lybellers aim, as a Servant of the Town,
be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe he is Captain of the Towns Guards: It is anſwered, that <hi>James
Baillie</hi> is a Gentleman, and a Merchant of a competent Fortune and Trade,
tho he be Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain of the Towns Guard, and was an ordinar Merchant-counſellor
the year preceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, when he had the ſame Employment, and it is abſurd
that he who could be an ordiner Counſellor the year preceeding, while he had
the ſame Employment, ſhould becauſe of that Employment, the next year be
incapable of Voting as an old Counſellor in the Leeting and Electing of
Magiſtrats. Likeas the Act of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vention expreſly appoints all Elections,
after the popular Election, to be according to the Set, and there is nothing
therein to hinder perſons that are old Counſellors the year preceeding, or
that are choſen Proxies, from Voting in the Leeting and Election of
Magiſtrats, tho they have Penſions from, or be Servants to the Town.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:172084:4"/>
            <p n="2">2. As to the pretended Informalities in the ſecond
Election, <hi>viz.</hi> 1. That <hi>Patrick Johnſtoun</hi> was then advanced
to be Baillie, though he was but twenty days a Counſellor before, which is
contrair to the 10 page of the Set, which appoints that no perſon be choſen
Magiſtrats, without they have been a Year or two on the Council before. It is
anſwered, That theſe words of the Set <hi>(An Year or two upon the
Council)</hi> are not to be underſtood that a Man muſt be a full Year upon
the Council before he be a Baillie, but that he muſt be a part of the Year
upon the Council before he be Baillie, and which hath been the conſtant
cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtom, as particularly in the caſe of <hi>Thomas Hamilton,</hi> who was
made a Baillie within eight days after he was made a Counſellor, and
<hi>Joſeph Majoribanks,</hi> after he was but a Month a Counſellor; and
which two were choſen Baillies for that ſame Year wherein they were made
new Counſellors, whereas <hi>Patrick John<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stoun</hi> was a Month a
Counſellor for the year preceeding, and the reſt of that year was Baillie
of <hi>Leith</hi> before he was choſen Baillie of <hi>Edinburgh;</hi> Likeas
<hi>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>lurg</hi> and <hi>William Paton,</hi> two of the Libellers
themſelves, were Elected Bail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies, when they were no longer Counſellors
than <hi>Patrick Johnſtoun</hi> was: And that the Paragraph Quoted by the
Libellers muſt be underſtood that <hi>Annus cep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tus pro completo
habetur,</hi> is evident by the 15. page, where it ſays, <hi>If any perſon
of the Merchants choſen upon the new Council, happen to be promoted to
another Office, another ſhall be choſen in his room:</hi> Which clearly
imports that a perſon of the new Merchant Council may be promoted to be a
Magiſtrat, ſince there is no other Office in the Council he can be promoted
to but a Magiſtrat. And if a perſon of the new Council can be promoted to
be a Baillie for that year he is choſen Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſellor in, it neceſſarly
imports, that a Man needs not be a whole year a Counſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor before he be
Elected Baillie, ſince generally thoſe of the new Council were never
Counſellors before, and therefore this Article, as it is groundleſs, ſo
is it ſhameleſly ſtated by the Libellers againſt the Defenders, ſince
ſome of themſelves were promoted that ſame way.</p>
            <p n="3">3. As to that pretence, that <hi>George Stirling</hi> was
continued more than two years on the Council, though the Set expreſly
provide, that no Man ſhall be upon the Council more than two Years, except he
be an Office-man, which <hi>George Stirling</hi> being a Trades-man, was not
capable of. It is anſwered, that <hi>George Stirling</hi> was Elected a
Trades-Counſellor by the Popular Election, and at the <hi>Michael<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſs</hi>
1689. he was choſen Deacon of the Chirurgions, and Deacon-Conveener of the
Trades, and was choſen as a Deacon to be Counſellor, wherein he continued
till <hi>Michaelmaſs</hi> 1691. And at <hi>Michaelmaſs</hi> 1691. was
choſen again to be a Trades-Counſellor, wherein he hath continued ſince;
ſo that <hi>George</hi> hath not been yet two years a Trades-Counſellor;
for the Libellers miſtake is this, that they do not think a Deacon an Office,
and that they confound a Deacon-Counſellor and a Trades-Counſellor; whereas
a Trades-Counſellor and a Deacon-Counſellor are contradiſtinct: And the
Paragraph of the Set alledged on, is immediatly ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyned to the method and
manner of chooſing the two Crafts-Counſellors; And it cannot be denyed but
a Deacon is an Office, and that the ſix ordinary Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cons are on the Council
as Deacons, and having that Office, whereas the other two Counſellors are on
as Trades-men, and are called Trade-Counſellors; ſo that <hi>George
Stirling</hi> having been continued on the Council in two diſtinct
Characters, he hath not contraveened that paſſage of the Set, nor did he
ever acknowledge any ſuch thing, and if he had, it was a miſtake, and
cannot hinder him to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue on the Council, when he is Elected according to
the Set; which is further cleared from the conſtant practice, ſo
<hi>William Hamilton</hi> Taylor continued eight years by changing his
Character of Deacon, Counſellor, and Trades-Counſellor; <pb n="8" facs="tcp:172084:5"/>and ſo <hi>Alexander Reid</hi> Gold-ſmith was continued ſix or
ſeven years on the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil.</p>
            <p n="3">3. As to the pretence anent <hi>William Carſe,</hi> that
he being one of the extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Deacons, was choſen to be one of the
ordinary Council of Twenty five, whereby the Council of Thirty eight was
reduced to Thirty ſeven, and the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders forced to chooſe <hi>Thomas
Campbel</hi> Proxie for <hi>William Carſe,</hi> when he was perſonally
preſent, to make up the number of Thirty eight perſons at the Electi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. It
is Anſwered, That there is nothing in the Set to hinder any of the eight
extraordinary Deacons to be Elected one of the two Trades-Counſellors, that
makes up the ordinar Council of Twenty five. And it were ſtrange, that when
any Trades-man might be Elected one of the two Trades-Counſellors, yet an
ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traordinary Deacon ſhould be incapable to be on the Council of Twenty
five, becauſe he is a Member of the Council of Thirty eight, when the whole
Twenty five Members of the oridinary Council, are all Members of the Council of
Thirty eight, as well as the eight extraordinary Deacons; and it is a miſtake
to aſſert that <hi>Thomas Campbel</hi> was Proxie for <hi>William
Carſe</hi> when he was preſent, for he was Proxie for the Deacon of the
Fleſhers, whoſe place was vacant, as one of the fourteen Trades, becauſe
of the advancement of <hi>William Carſe</hi> to be an ordinary Counſellor,
who in that Character could not repreſent the Incorporation of the
Fleſhers. And this ſame was practiſed when Sir <hi>Thomas Kennedy</hi>
was Provoſt, in the caſe of <hi>John Robiſon</hi> Litſter, who being
Deacon of that Trade, and ſo a Member of the Council of Thirty eight, was
advanced to be upon the Council of Twenty five; And at the enſuing Election,
another of that Corporation was brought in to Vote for that Trade, and to make
up the number of Thirty eight by Perſons at the Election.</p>
            <p n="3">3. As to pretended Informalities in the Election of the
preſent Magiſtracy at <hi>Michaelmaſs</hi> laſt, as 1. That of
<hi>William Carſe</hi> his Voting, both Perſonally and by Proxie, is
anſwered already.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That Proxies being choſen and admitted to Vote
ſeveral days before, were thrown out by a Vote the day of the Election,
contrair to the Set, page 16. and 17. <hi>Which appoints the thirty perſons,
who made the Leets, to make up with the eight extraordinary Deacons, the thirty
eight Electors,</hi> and yet at this Election, theſe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xies were thrown out
that Voted the Leeting. It is anſwered, that the Words of the Set, page 16.
and 17. are oppon'd, which does not bear, that the thirty perſons that
Leeted, and the eight extraordinary Deacons, ſhould make up the number of
thirty eight Counſellors; but that the thirty perſons of the old and new
Council, &amp;c. And the Libellers cannot ſubſume that any of the old or
new Counſellors were excluded, and for the changing of Proxies at the
Councils pleaſure, there is nothing that hinders it by the Set, otherways a
Proxie would be in the ſame Caſe with an ordinary Member of the old or new
Council, which makes up the number of the thirty, if they could not be removed
at plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure; Likeas the Proxies that were thrown out the day of Election,
were only called in, and allowed to Vote the preceeding day of the Leeting, and
were not called in the day of Election, and ſo the Council had reaſon to
throw them out by a Vote, who officiouſly intruded themſelves that day
without an invitation.</p>
            <p n="3">3. As to that pretence, that the Proxies who had Voted to
the Leeting, were thrown out the day of Election, without the allowing Eight
extraordinary Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cons to Vote, whether theſe Proxies ſhould be continued
or not: It is anſwered, that the Eight extraordinary Deacons are to Vote in
the Election of Magiſtrats, and <pb n="9" facs="tcp:172084:5"/>other Matters of Import
mentioned in the <hi>Pag.</hi> 18. of the Set; But the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrats are to be
Leeted by the Old and New Council conſiſting of Thirty (whereof the
Extraordinary Deacons are no part) and if there by any of the Thirty abſent,
thoſe of that Number of Thirty are to chuſe Proxies for the Abſents: As
is clear by the Set, <hi>Page</hi> 19. which provides no Proxies to be
cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen for Deacons, but only the preceeding Deacon to be called; and
therefore ſince Proxies can only be choſen for the abſents of the Thirty;
theſe Proxies can only be choſen by theſe preſent of the Thirty.</p>
            <p n="4">4. As to the pretence of the not reading the Set, and taking
the ſolemn proteſtation accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly. It is anſwered, that this pretence
is Falſe and Calumnious: For at that time the Lord <hi>Provoſt</hi>
Replyed, that they by their Oath <hi>de fideli,</hi> were bound to give the
Voice of their Conſcience: and the ſaid <hi>Robert</hi> continuing to urge
an Oath to be impoſed: the Lord <hi>Provost</hi> told them, they were to give
the Votes of their Conſciences, as in the preſence of GOD, whereunto they
all gave their Aſſent, and in particular the ſaid <hi>Robert
Blackwood,</hi> in face of Council acknowledged he was fully ſatisfied
therewith: whereupon Inſtruments were taken, and which can be proven by
Witneſs thereupon.</p>
            <p n="5">5. As to that pretence anent <hi>George Stirlings</hi>
Declaration that he would continue no longer on the Council, and his retreating
thereof. The ſame is anſwered already, for if <hi>George</hi> might be
continued by the Set longer then two Years, changing his Character from Deacon
Counſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, to Tradeſ-Counſellour, as he might for the Reaſons
above-written, then his own Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, though he had given it (which is
denied) yet ſince he gave it by miſtake, he may retreat the ſame.</p>
            <p n="6">6. As to Baillie <hi>Bowdouns</hi> being Elected, when he
was not a Counſellor, a full year before; it is the ſame caſe with
<hi>Patrick Johnſtoun,</hi> which is anſwered already.</p>
            <p n="7">7. As to the pretence againſt <hi>William Menzies,</hi>
that though he could only continue two years Theſaurer, and one year
Old-Theſaurer on the Counſel; yet he has continued more without being in
any other Office, than Theſaurer, which is contrair to the Set; Eſpecially
not having made his Accompts; And by the two years Act it is provided, That no
Theſaurer can be made a Baillie, till he make his Accompts; and that the
ſaid <hi>William</hi> has got a Gratification of an hundred pounds Sterling
from the Town, for his being Ring-leader of that Faction (as they call it.) It
is Anſwered. That <hi>William Menzies</hi> being choſen Theſaurer, at the
popular Election he dimitted his Office at <hi>Martimaſs</hi> 1690. and ſo
might have continued a year upon the Counſel as Old-Theſaurer; But in
<hi>June</hi> 1691, when Sir <hi>Archibald Muir</hi> was choſen Provoſt, he
was Elected youngeſt of the four Old Baillies; in which ſtation he
continued till<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>Michael<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſs</hi> laſt, at which time he was
Elected Old Dean of Guild; whereby it is clear, that he was never a ſingle
Merchant Counſellor ſince the Revolution; and ſo is not concerned in the
continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance longer than two years, ſince all the time he was either
preſent Theſaurer, Old-Theſaurer, Old-Baillie, or Old-Dean of Gild; which
four Capacities are all Offices; and any perſon may continue upon the Council
longer than two years, when they are choſen ſucceſſive to dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferent
Offices. And for his not making his Accompts, that delay is occaſioned by
<hi>James M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>lurg,</hi> and the other
Auditors, who would not clear his accompts of purpoſe to hinder him from
being Elected a Baillie, ſo that it is incompetent to and malitious in them
to obtrude his not clearing of his accompts, he having Several times required
them to audite the ſame, and take inſtruments upon their Delay, and it is
moſt falſe that he is indebted any Conſiderable Reſt to the Town, for
he could make it appear that there is not four hundred pounds ſcots in his
band; and as to the Gratification of an hundred pounds ſterling allowed him,
it was allowed him for his neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſar Charges and Expenſes the ninteen
Months he was Theſaurer, and is leſs than ever was allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to any former
Theſaurer for their incident Charges.</p>
            <p n="8">8. As to the pretence, that <hi>George Stirling</hi> had a
Proxy Voting for him, as an old Counſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, when he himſelf was
preſent, and Voted as a preſent Counſellour. It is Anſwered, That there
is nothing more rational and conſiſtent with the Set, than to Elect an old
Tradeſ-Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſellour, <pb n="10" facs="tcp:172084:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>who has not been two years
upon the Counſel as a Tradeſ-Counſellour: and to Vo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> him a preſent Tradeſ-Counſellour before his two
years run out; and his place of the O<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Tradeſ-Counſellour not being filled, to fill up the ſame by
a Proxy, to make up the number <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
thirty; which Proxy was not a Proxy for <hi>George Stirling,</hi> who was
preſent, but a Pro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> for the Old
Tradeſ-Counſellour, which was vacant by <hi>George</hi>'s being made
preſent Tradeſ-Cou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſellour.</p>
            <p n="9">9. As to that pretence, that the ſaid <hi>George
Stirling,</hi> and other Deacons mentioned the Libel, did enter into a
Conſpiracy, and ſubſcribe a Paper to Elect Sir <hi>John Ha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Provoſt.</p>
            <p>It is anſwered; That the alledgance is altogether falſe, and
the Defenders denies the ſam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>In reſpect of all whch, and that the Complaint is only at
the Inſtance of Nine Perſons, wher<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> of five Merchants,</hi> viz. James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>lurg, George Clerk, William
Paton, Rober Blac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>wood <hi>and</hi>
Duncan M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>intoſh; <hi>and four Tradeſmen.</hi> viz. James Penman, William
Sco<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Wright.</hi> Robert Ioglis
<hi>and</hi> Andrew Paterſon, <hi>of which number ſeven of them are
priv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> perſons, and the other two
only Deacons out of Doors, the Defenders ought to be Aſſoilzi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> from the malicious and ſcandalons
Complaint exhibite againſt them by the Complainers and the Defenders Libel of
Re-convention ought to be admitted to Probation.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
